important news coming in for the
country's largest lender State Bank of
India the banks sport Bureau has
recommended denesh Kumar Kara for the
wancy of the post of the chairman of
State Bank of India now current chairman
rajnish Kumar's term comes to an end on
October 7th this year he had a
three-year term he was appointed as
chairman in October 2017 now what's
important to note is that this is a
recommendation by the Banks board Bureau
this may or may not be taken up by the
government but it is very likely that
the government is will not refuse the
recommendation that has been given by
the Banks board Bureau and in that case
what will happen is rajnish Kumar will
not be getting an extension as chairman
and theh Kumar K will take over as
chairman of State Bank of India now what
the banks board Bureau has also said
that they are recommending CS Shetty as
a candidate on the reserve list for the
said vacancy apart from that the banks
Bo Bureau had actually spoken to all
four MDS they had interviewed all four
MDS of State Bank of India including
Arijit Basu adesh Kumar Kara Cs shetti
and Ashwini bhia but they have zeroed in
on the name of Danesh Kumar k for the
name of the chairman next chairman at
State Bank of India talking a little bit
about Danesh Kumar Kara he had joined
SBI as a probationary officer in
1984 he has over 33 years of experience
in all facets of Commercial Banking
including retail credit corporate credit
uh deposit mobilization International
banking Operations Branch management Etc
so he comes from a vast he has a vast
experience within SBI this is a name
that the banks sport Bureau has chosen
from the existing MDS and someone who is
within the banking system within SBI
since 33 years so the transition may not
be a problem in case the government goes
ahead with this and very important to
know that this announcement this change
will come in at a very peculiar and very
important time for the government for
the state for State Bank of India and
this is because we are in the midst of a
pandemic we are still awaiting the final
decision of RBI and the final circular
of RBI on onetime restructuring after
the KV K committee gives its
recommendations as to how it will go
through and only over the next few
months we will understand the level of
npas that the banks will pile up or the
balance sheet impact that uh you know
finally the banks have had because of
covid-19 and the impact coming in from
covid-19 now additionally uh Danesh
Kumar Kar was also the MD and CEO of SBI
funds management before being appointed
as MD at State Bank of India and he was
very instrumental mainly in merging SBI
with the five associate Banks and with
bhartia mahila bank so now all eyes
definitely will be on the government's
decision 7th October is when rajes
Kumar's ter term ends so before that a
call will be taken by the government but
it is likely that the government will
accept the BP bureau's decision and go
ahead with dises Kumar Kara and that
case will rule out an extension for
rajes Kumar